Enrique Alonso Esposito

Software Developer with over four years of experience in the field. Consistently and efficiently collaborated in medium sized teams to develop cross platform Mobile applications and support senior engineers. I am committed, deadline-driven and a team player.

EXPERIENCE

Vincle International, Madrid, Spain - Software Developer

Software developer - January 2020 - March 2024

Among the performed tasks:

- Used .NET's Xamarin.Forms to create multi-platform mobile applications for iOS, Android and UWP
- Developed both the **GUI** and **logic** of the apps.
- Collaborated with the UI/UX designers to build attractive and responsive designs.
- Used local **SQLite** databases and queries to store and read large amounts of data through complex **SQL queries**.
- Used custom **APIs** to retrieve and send data to the backend.
- Used **GIT** to organize projects, versions and feature branches as well as to collaborate in a team of multiple developers.
- Followed multiple develop methodologies (Agile: Scrum & Kanban)
- Designed and executed test plans and suites in Azure to ensure product quality.
- Took part in the building of two important projects for the company using MVC and MVVM architectures.

Montamar Real Estate, Marbella, Spain - Interior Photographer

Summer months of 2015 - 2018

EDUCATION

California State University San Marcos

Bachelor Of Science in Computer Science - 08/2015 - 06/2019

Major GPA: 3.14 & Dean's list

Fab Friday Program, CSUSM - Viasat QA App

02/2019 - 05/2019

Collaborated with a small group of students to design, create, test and document a cross-platform mobile QA app and API for Viasat.

Developed technical and soft skills essential for Software Developers as

SKILLS

- Fast Learner
- Good Teamwork Skills
- Deadline-driven
- Detail Oriented

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

- C#
- XAML
- SQL

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Net & Xamarin.Forms
- Visual Studio & Code
- Git
- Postman
- Agile
- Scrum & Kanban
- API integration
- Microsoft Azure
- MVC & MVVM

FAMILIAR WITH

- HTML & CSS
- ANGULAR

LANGUAGES

- Spanish (Native)
- English (Bilingual)

well as learned new languages and frameworks under very demanding deadlines.

Closely worked with industry and faculty mentors.

PROJECTS

Vincle For Sales 2: Mobile App

A cross platform CRM / SFA mobile application for high consumer and Pharma. This application allows presales users to create new customers, take orders, plan routes, do inventory among many other features. For doing so most operations are stored and read in a local **SQLite** database during visits and data is sent back to the office's servers through API communications at user's will.

Used Xamarin.Forms, SQL, REST apis and a MVC architecture.

Vincle For Sales 2: B2B App

In addition to the Mobile app, this app was built to allow final users to place, modify and track orders on their own; visualize product data, sales conditions and promotions; get in contact with customer support through a live chat; and perform many other tasks. This application relies heavily on REST api communications as all data is fetched and stored in the servers.

Used Syncfusion componentes to create a modern, intuitive and responsive UI that met the UI/UX team requirements.

Used Xamarin.Forms, REST apis, Syncfusion and a MVVM architecture.

${\bf Sahara\ Mobile\ Shopping\ Application\ (School)}$

A cross-platform mobile shopping application that replicates features of Amazon, Ebay and other well known shopping apps.

Developed using **Xamarin.Forms**, **C#** and **XAML**. Uses a **MVC** architecture and requires a server to communicate with a database.

Sahara Server (School)

Linked to the previous project, a **TCP** server was created in order to handle incoming requests from the client app.

Thanks to specifically created event handlers we can read and write data using short SQL statements into the **SQLite** database.

Developed using C# and SQL.

POKEnhanced (School)

A cross-platform mobile application for Pokemon enthusiasts. This app allows the user to search for their favorite pokemons, add them to their team and visualize unique information. Twitter's API is implemented in order to display Pokemon relevant tweets.

Designed a clean, attractive and intuitive GUI.